Today I'm going to show you how you can transform a learning path into a real learning tool, not just a translator.
And today I'm not going to talk in general, but I'm going to use specific prompts and requests that you can create.
For example, today I'm going to show all this on the A1 line, but this video is not only for beginners.
You will be able to adapt all this as well, because we will be building a learning system.
And you will be able to find ready-made prompts for your level in the pinned comment under this video on my Telegram channel.
And our first step is the base. You need to know what level of learning you have now.
That is, it is not ok to write something like A2 or B1.
You need to know your level, because then your GPT will not be able to put the program specifically for you.
It will be either something very easy or very difficult, on the contrary.
In this case, I have a ready-made prompt for you, which you can copy and paste for your chat.
I'm going to read it now.
You are a certified English language teacher. Help me define my level of English.
Create a series of tasks that check the lexicon, grammar, understanding of the text, speaking.
Go step by step, step by step.
After my answers, explain what this means for my level and tell me what it is.
And in 20-30 minutes you will have a real understanding of where you are now and where you need to go next.
And then there is another critically important point, which I constantly see as a mistake.
That people open a lot of chats and try to learn from them.
But it is very important to open only one chat and learn from it.
Because then this chat will remember everything about you.
What mistakes you have made, what you have not said, what you have already gone through, what needs to be fixed again.
And when you open a new chat, this memory is not saved and you seem to go through the same thing again.
So we fix one chat, one teacher.
Well, now our second step.
Now we will create the same teacher who will teach us.
And let's read this prompt. You can copy it later.
I am learning English. My level is one. Here you can set your level.
Learn me as a patient teacher, from simple to difficult, in short steps, with constant repetition, without overloading.
Work with me in one chat. Remember my typical mistakes.
Come back to them later.
First explain, then give practice, then repeat.
Speak simply and understandably.
And with this step you make a very important thing.
When you speak, you don't just open another random chat.
You make your constant, constant teacher.
Well, you have already created your teacher.
You gave him the goal.
Now let's go to practice.
The next step we need to get from him certain ready-made phrases that correspond to our level.
What are we writing to him?
Here I have 10 very simple English phrases for level A1 on the subject of acquaintance without grammatical explanations.
Look, here you can also replace the level and the topic on which you want to get these phrases.
But in general, I think the logic has understood.
And look what he will send us. I will add a screenshot here.
Here he sends directly.
Okay, here are 10 very simple phrases for level A1 on the subject of acquaintance.
And there is a parallel.
Hello, hi, my name is Anna. And so on.
In principle, he has done his job.
He sent you not just words, but whole ready-made phrases.
And I think you should already know that in English you need to learn not with separate words, but with ready-made vocabulary.
The next step will be listening and a prompt for listening.
Read these phrases in a slow voice.
And now I will show you how it works.
Of course.
I will now read them clearly and slowly so that it is easy for you to repeat.
Ready? Let's go.
First.
Hello.
Second.
Hi.
Third.
My name is Anna.
Fourth.
I am Anna.
Fifth.
What is your name?
Sixth.
Nice to meet you.
Seventh.
I am from Ukraine.
Eighth.
Where are you from?
Ninth.
How are you?
Tenth.
I am fine.
I will repeat how many you need.
If necessary, tell them more.
That's right.
Look what's important here.
You can listen to it more than once.
I advise you to listen to it more than once.
In order to fix this in your head,
your brain will work better
and will be able to recognize it in real life.
It will also be able to give you options for these phrases
when you speak English yourself.
So listen as much as possible.
By the way, in terms of how to listen to it all,
I will add a screenshot here.
You need to click on something
to sound what was written.
The next step will be reading.
And not some random reading,
but reading exactly what you have been working with.
That is, we will polish again
those phrases and phrases that you have read
and heard recently
and what will be the basis for this.
Look.
Let's create a monologue, a story,
a text for reading,
5-6 sentences for level A1 with these phrases.
It should sound like a living language,
one paragraph, logically connected sentences,
without a list and without separate phrases
that can be said in one breath.
And now I will show you what he created for me.
Here I add a screenshot of his answer.
And what to do with it.
You can read it in your head.
Maybe not even once.
You can ask him to sound it again
through the button that I have already shown you.
And what is important here is that your brain
perceives that he has heard somewhere before
and he begins to remember.
And at this moment you are really learning.
And now we will move on to grammar.
But I will not ask him now
that he wrote me the rules of use.
I will ask him to explain it to me.
And see what we can write to him.
Explain, very simply,
what does I am mean
without grammatical terms and difficult explanations.
See that he answers me.
I am is what you say about yourself.
When you want to say who you are,
what you are, how you feel,
you start with I am.
And examples of life go on.
As for me, the explanation is super,
there are no difficult terms,
there are no difficult times.
It's just logical, understandable,
and at the beginning it's just great.
Of course, if it's a different word,
it will be a bit complicated.
You will see it all in the prompt.
But for now, the logic is as follows.
Well, now there will be my favorite stage.
The stage when we start talking with our chat.
Again, through this button,
we have to switch to the conversation mode.
And what do we say?
Let's now make a simple dialogue
in English for level A1 with you.
You are a new person for me,
and ask me simple questions in turns.
Of course, that's fine.
Let's start a simple dialogue,
and I'll ask questions in turns.
First question.
What is your name?
My name is Anastasia.
Nice to meet you, Anastasia.
Where are you from?
I am from Ukraine.
That's great.
What do you like to do in your free time?
I like cooking and training.
That sounds fun.
Can you tell me if you are learning English right now?
I think that you got it,
that I'm learning English right now.
Absolutely.
I just wanted to hear you say it.
You are doing great.
Keep it up.
That's about it.
If he says something wrong at some stage,
you can just give him some information
about it, so that he can answer your questions,
because he can sometimes give them straight to the list.
But in general,
you can also ask him to translate
each question,
or make some mistakes when you answer them.
So, use it.
After that, we will practice writing.
I always say seven.
The more you write, the better you speak.
So, keep it up for writing.
Help me write three simple sentences
about yourself in English for the level A1.
Now I'll show you another answer.
Look, I'll add.
First, he wrote me some patterns
that I can use.
Then he gives you three steps,
so that you can write these three sentences to him.
In this case, when you write your sentences to him,
he will correct you if something goes wrong,
or he will praise you if you wrote everything correctly.
And now a very important nuance.
After each lesson,
you must record your progress.
You must help this machine
to record everything that has happened.
What will you write to it?
Also a prompt.
Make a short summary of the lesson.
What have we gone through?
What mistakes are repeated?
What should we repeat next time?
No more than 100 words.
Look, you can put it all at the end of this lesson
and at the beginning of the next one,
so that you really don't forget
what you have already gone through
And now there will be a very logical question
probably from you.
Okay, I practiced it today,
what should I do next?
How to do it all on your own?
And I'll tell you,
you don't need to guess the bike,
because I already guessed it for you.
You just need to copy this prompt
and then move along our already created roadmap.
Look at the prompt.
Take an English lesson every day for level A1.
One lesson, one day.
Let's start with a short repetition
of what we have already gone through.
2-3 minutes.
In the repetition, use the same words
and constructions as before.
After each step, stop and wait.
The structure of the lesson.
A short repetition.
A short explanation of a new topic.
8-10 simple phrases.
Read them out loud.
A short star text.
A simple explanation of the meaning of the constructions.
A short dialogue.
A short letter.
Speak simply and don't overload.
And that's it.
ChargPT will take you further as a real teacher.
It's just magic, I think.
And about these prompts.
They are written under the general learning system.
If you need a specific topic,
or look at a specific grammatical structure,
and so on, you can correct it.
So adapt.
ChargPT is not a repeater.
But with a well-developed system,
you can create a real working trainer with it.
That's why it's important to create this very system
so that it's not chaotic,
but as disassembled as we disassembled today.
Because that's how our brain dominates all subjects.
So, if you found it useful, interesting,
liked it,
I will be very grateful for your support.
Like, comment, subscribe.
Well, I've already said that.
And I want to remind you that under this video,
in the pinned comment,
you will see the link to my Telegram channel,
where all the prompts for each level will be collected.
Bye-bye.